karelia.com 2016-03-05

# Privacy Policy | Karelia Software

This policy addresses how Karelia Software LLC, a California limited liability company, (“Karelia,” “we,” “us,” or “our”) and its affiliated products, web sites, and services (including but not limited to www.karelia.com, and referred to as “Karelia Products, Sites, and Services”) treat personal information that we collect and receive. Personal information is generally defined as information about you that is personally identifiable (such as your name, address, email address, or phone number) and that is not otherwise publicly available.

This policy does not apply to the practices of companies that we do not own or control, or to people that we do not employ or manage.

Karelia Products, Sites, and Services use information for the following general purposes: for products and services provision; for billing; for identification and authentication; for services improvement; in order to contact you; for research; and for anonymous reporting.

**What Information?**

Karelia Products, Sites, and Services may collect personal information (such as, but not limited to, your name, email address, billing address, and phone number) when you register with them, and/or use the particular products or services. Karelia Products, Sites, and Services may collect personal information about you if and when you enter into promotions or sweepstakes, or when you participate in product or service testing and feedback.

Karelia Products, Sites, and Services may combine information about you that we have with information we obtain from business partners or others.

Karelia Products, Sites, and Services may automatically receive and record information on our server logs from your browser, including your IP address, cookies, and the pages you request, specifically:

          IP addresses:  Karelia Products, Sites, and Services may obtain IP addresses from users depending upon how you access our web sites. IP addresses, browser, and session information may be used for various purposes, including but not limited to: (1) diagnose and prevent service or technology problems reported by our users or engineers that are associated with the IP addresses controlled by a specific web company or ISP; (2) estimate the total number of users visiting our web sites from specific geographical regions; (3) help determine which users have access privileges to certain content, services or resources that we may offer; (4) monitor and prevent fraud and abuse.

          Cookies:  A cookie is generally defined as a small amount of data, which often includes an anonymous unique identifier that is sent to your browser from a web site’s computers and stored on your computer’s hard drive. If you reject all cookies, you may not be able to use Karelia Products, Sites, and Services if you are required to log in, and you may not be able to take full advantage of all offerings. Karelia Products, Sites, and Services use their own cookies for a number of purposes, including to: (1) keep track of preferences you specify while you are using Karelia Products, Sites, and Services; (2) estimate and report our total visitor size and traffic; and (3) conduct research to improve the content and services provided by or on Karelia Products, Sites, and Services, including but not limited to determining the version of the Karelia Product, Site, or Service being launched or requested, the version of the operating system in use, and your first four language preferences.

For customers and website visitors from the European Union: With regards to the European Union’s cookie directive that will be effective in May 2012, be advised that Sandvox itself does not employ cookies; however, individual plugins, including but not limited to Google Analytics, do use cookies which may require disclosure and consent under the EU directive. At present, the cookie settings on Karelia’s websites are set to “allow all cookies” to improve the efficiency of your visit and to provide us with analytic feedback about visitors’ experiences. Viewing or otherwise engaging with Karelia’s websites signifies your consent to the use of such cookies; if you do not wish to allow cookies, you should change your browser’s cookie settings before continuing.

**Information Use, Sharing, and Disclosure**

Karelia Products, Sites, and Services do not share personal information we learn about you from your use of our products, web sites, and services with others except as described in this policy. We do not share your information with unrelated third parties for their direct marketing purposes.

When you provide personal information through using Karelia Products, Sites, and Services you are sharing your personal information with Karelia Software and its affiliated entities. The use of your personal information by these organizations is subject to this policy.

Karelia Products, Sites, and Services may use or share your personal information where it is necessary to complete a transaction, to operate or improve Karelia Products, Sites, and/or Services, to do something that you have asked us to do, or to tell you of products and services that we think may be of interest.

Where you are contacted with an offer or service based on information you have shared with any Karelia Products, Sites, and/or Services we will do our best to provide you with an opportunity to opt-out of receiving such further communications at the time you are contacted; however, in connection with any of our paid products and services (i.e., products or services that you license or use for a fee), we reserve the right to send you certain communications relating to those products and services, such as service announcements and administrative messages, without offering you the opportunity to opt-out of receiving them.

If you post personal information online that is accessible to the public, you may receive unsolicited messages from other parties in return.

Karelia Products, Sites, and Services may share personally identifiable information about you under the following circumstances:

          (1) In the course of operating our business it may be necessary or appropriate for us to provide access to your personal information to others such as our service providers, contractors, and select vendors so that we can operate Karelia Products, Sites, and Services and our business. Where practical, we seek to obtain confidentiality agreements that are consistent with this policy and that limit others’ use or disclosure of the information you have shared. 

          (2) We may share your personal information to respond to subpoenas, court orders, or legal process, to establish or exercise our legal rights, or to defend against legal claims and if, in our judgment in such circumstances, disclosure is required or appropriate.

          (3) We may share your personal information if we believe it is necessary in order to investigate, prevent, or take action regarding illegal activities, suspected fraud, situations involving potential threats to the physical safety of any person, violations of our various terms of use, or as otherwise required by law.

As we continue to develop our business, we may also sell all or part of our business. In such transactions, personally identifiable information you have shared with us is generally one of the business assets that will be transferred. The transferred personally identifiable information will remain subject to the promises made in this privacy policy or subsequent policies to which you have consented.

 **Do Not Track**

Our websites do not track your online activities over time and across third-party Web sites.  Because we do not employ tracking technology, we offer no response to “Do Not Track” requests transmitted by Web browsers.

**Children and Their Information**

We do not, at present, collect any personally identifying information from children or from individuals who could be recognized as minors. If we do so in the future, we will comply with the requirements of the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act (“COPPA”).

**Changes to this Privacy Policy**

We may revise, modify, or update this policy. We will notify you about significant changes in the way we treat personal information by placing a prominent notice on our site.

**Confidentiality and Security**

No data transmissions over the Internet can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. Consequently, we cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to us and you do so at your own risk. Once we receive your transmission, we make efforts to ensure security on our systems. We use physical, electronic, and procedural safeguards to protect personal information about you.

In certain areas, Karelia Products, Sites, and Services use industry-standard SSL-encryption to protect data transmissions. This is not, however, a guarantee that such information may not be accessed, disclosed, altered, or destroyed by breach of such firewalls and secure server software.

If we learn of a security breach we may attempt to notify you electronically so that you can take appropriate protective steps. By using Karelia Products, Sites, and Services or by providing personal information to us you agree that we can communicate with you electronically regarding security, privacy, and administrative issues relating to your use of those products, sites, and services. We may post a notice on our applicable web site(s) if a security breach occurs. If this happens, you will need a web browser enabling you to view the applicable web site(s). We may also send an email to you at the email address you have provided to us in these circumstances. Depending on where you live, you may have a legal right to receive notice of a security breach in writing. To receive free written notice of a security breach (or to withdraw your consent from receiving electronic notice) you should notify us at privacy@karelia.com.

**Contacting Karelia**

If you have a privacy concern regarding any Karelia Product, Site, or Service, or regarding this policy, and if you cannot satisfactorily resolve it through the use of those products, sites, or services, you can write to us by email at privacy@karelia.com. Alternatively, we can be reached at our postal mail address:

Karelia Software  
Attention: Privacy Matters   
2532 Santa Clara Ave. #273  
Alameda CA 94501 USA

If you object to any sharing of your personal information that may be permitted under this policy, you may do so by writing us at the above address. We will take reasonable steps to accommodate your requests as they relate to our practices. In some instances, honoring your requests may interfere with or preclude your ability to use Karelia Products, Sites, and Services or may require us to terminate our relationship with you.

Effective Date: December 19, 2005; amended October 6, 2015
